The sport made him a legend. His heart made him a hero.
8 Seconds is a drama, romance, western film directed by John G. Avildsen.
This film chronicles the life of Lane Frost, 1987 PRCA Bull Riding World Champion, his marriage
and his friendships with Tuff Hedeman (three-time World Champion) and Cody Lambert.
Lane Frost, played by Luke Perry.
Tuff Hedeman, played by Stephen Baldwin.
Cody Lambert, played by Red Mitchell.
Kellie Frost, played by Cynthia Geary.
Clyde Frost, played by James Rebhorn.
Elsie Frost, played by Carrie Snodgress.
8 Seconds is a 1994 American contemporary western
biographical drama film directed by John G.
Its title refers to the length of time a bull rider is
required to stay on for a ride to be scored.
The film stars Luke Perry as American rodeo legend Lane Frost and
focuses on his life and career as a bull riding champion.
It also features Stephen Baldwin as Tuff Hedeman,
and Red Mitchell as Cody Lambert.
The film was completed and premiered shortly after what would
have been Frost's 30th birthday, in late 1993.
The film was released by New Line Cinema on February 25, 1994.
The film explores themes of rodeo, cowboy, bull riding.
The tone is emotional.